创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning there was darkness
随着一声爆炸
and then, bang--
诞生了无尽膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
每一天 新的发现都在揭秘这个诡异
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
震撼 神秘莫测的
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
地方 - 我们所谓的《宇宙》
of a place we call "The Universe."
它们是宇宙的怪胎 -
They are the freaks of the cosmos--
脉冲星与类星体
pulsars and quasars.
它们怪异到连生存都似乎不大可能
So strange, their very existence seems impossible.
它们必须是巨人 十足的怪兽
They must be titanic, absolute monsters.
是什么让它们发出十亿个太阳的光辉
What makes them shine with the light of a billion suns,
旋转比眨眼都快
rotate faster than the blink of an eye,
或爆发出的宇宙节奏
or bang out cosmic rhythms
与《感恩而死》的鼓手一般？
with the drummer from The Grateful Dead?
一旦我开始全身心投入
Once all of these things started to come my way
我就意识到 知道吗 宇宙在欢唱
I realized that, you know, the universe was singing.
然而那是个怪得离奇的曲调
But it's a tune bizarre beyond imagination,
因为脉冲星与类星体 -
with pulsars and quasars
天文插曲的超级明星
the superstars of an astronomical sideshow
只能出现在宇宙最怪异的地方
found only in the strangest sectors of the universe.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.hdcmct.com
影片压制:暮云春树  字幕来源：HDC字幕组 调校：晴天 招募Q号: 76846146
历史频道 - 宇宙 第4季第10集 脉冲星和类星体
The History Channel - The Universe s04e10 Pulsar & Quasars
1967年 地球上的科学家取得了一项惊人的发现
In 1967, scientists on planet Earth made a startling discovery.
有东西 有人 正通过太空向我们发送信号
Something, someone, was sending us signals through space.
莫非是外星人在向我们发送信息么？
Were aliens trying to send us a message?
脉冲星首次发现时 让我们大吃一惊
When pulsars were first discovered, they blew us away.
夜空中有东西在不停地打开关闭
Something in the night sky was turning on and off.
自然界怎么会有东西在干那事的呢？
How could something in nature do that?
因而我们就把它们叫做继电器对象
And so we actually called them LGM objects.
那代表了小绿人
That stood for little green men.
英国天文学家检测到了信号
Astronomers in England detected the signals
利用的是早期的射电望远镜
using a primitive radio telescope,
一个庞大的电线和电杆的列阵 占据了四英亩多的土地
a massive array of poles and wires stretched out over four acres of land.
首批信号
The first of the signals
并不只是孤立的无线电噪音的波峰
was not just an isolated peak in the radio noise.
那是有规律的脉冲 每1.3秒精准地重复一次
It was a regular blip, precisely repeating every 1.3 seconds.
然而 在当年 科学家就意识到
Within a year, though, scientists realized
有规律的信号背后并无外星人
aliens were not behind the regular signals.
相反 它们出自快速旋转的恒星
Instead, they came from rapidly rotating stars.
“脉冲星”成了新现象抢眼的名字
"Pulsar" became the catchy name for the new phenomenon,
是脉动恒星的简称
short for pulsating star.
脉冲星看上去在不停地眨眼
A pulsar seems to blink on and off
因为旋转的恒星正从其磁场中发出能量束
because the rotating star is sending out beams of energy from its magnetic field,
并没有与其旋转轴保持一致
which is not aligned with its axis of rotation.
当其经过我们的视野时 我们看到闪光般的光束
We see the beam as a flash of light when it passes across our field of view.
脉冲星发出的光束原理很大程度就像这个警灯
The beam coming out of a pulsar works a lot like this emergency beacon.
现在来看看它是如何闪烁的
Now take a look at how it flashes.
它不仅在不停地闪烁
It's not just blinking on and off.
在外罩里 警灯有一个旋转的反射镜
Inside the housing, the beacon has a rotating reflector
把光线360度地扫射
that sweeps the light around 360 degrees.
只要我们有光束的基准线
As long as we have line of sight with the beam,
它每次转动都会掠过我们
it sweeps by us every time it goes around.
不过它看上去就是断断续续的闪烁
But it looks like it's flashing on and off.
旋转的脉冲星看来不停闪烁是同样的道理
A rotating pulsar looks like it is flashing on and off for the same reason.
然而脉冲星并不只是随便那种旋转的恒星
But a pulsar isn't just any kind of rotating star.
它是旋转的中子星
It's a rotating neutron star,
一种怪异的物体 诞生于大质量恒星以超新星结束生命之时
an exotic object created when a big, massive star ends its life in a supernova.
天体物理学家帕特.斯莱恩用一个迷人的方法向我们演示
Astrophysicist Pat Slane has a fascinating way to show us
超新星爆发后留下的东西
what's left over after the supernova,
恒星残核的压力
when the pressure of the star's remaining core
已不再能够抵抗重力了
can no longer fight against the force of gravity.
我在这里要演示的
What I'm going to demonstrate here
是我们从这个55加仑的罐子里抽去空气后的情景
is what happens when we remove the air from the interior of this 55-gallon drum
让地球的大气 空气的重量来压垮它
and let the atmosphere of the Earth, the weight of the air, crush it.
这类似于大质量恒星内部在其晚年所发生的情景
This is similar to what happens at the interior of a massive star late in its life.
在其失去压力支撑后
When it loses its pressure support,
恒星开始垮塌 就有了一个超新星爆发
the star collapses, and there's a supernova explosion.
垮塌后的恒星残骸变成了中子星
The crushed stellar remnant becomes the neutron star
质量是我们太阳的1.4倍
with a mass 1.4 times our Sun
缩小到了曼哈顿大小的球体
reduced to a sphere the size of Manhattan.
它是世上最离奇的物体之一
It is one of the most bizarre objects in nature.
你必须明白中子星
You have to understand that a neutron star
是在垮塌成黑洞之前勉强支撑的物体
is matter barely holding up before it collapses into a black hole.
其引力强大到
The gravity is so strong
将电子压进了原子核
that it has crushed electrons into the nucleus of an atom
从而变成了中子
and made neutrons.
令人拍案
It's amazing.
如果你有方糖那样的东西 举个例子
If you take something like a sugar cube, for example,
约一立方厘米
about a cubic centimeter.
如果这方糖是由中子星材料构成的
If this sugar cube were made of neutron star material,
它就会有近十亿吨重
it would weigh close to a billion tons.
想想8000艘航母的东西
Think of it as something like 8,000 aircraft carriers
在那么大的 密度大得难以置信的物体里头
in something that size, incredibly dense objects.
新诞生的中子星会不由自主地产生高速旋转
The newly created neutron star can't help having a high-speed spin.
所有的恒星 我们知道都在旋转
All stars that we know about are already rotating,
因此当大质量恒星压缩成中子星后
so when a massive star compresses into a neutron star,
旋转同样被压缩了
the rotation is compressed also.
这就像是滑冰者
It's just like an ice skater.
当滑冰者旋转收拢她的双臂
When an ice skater spins and she pulls her arms in,
就会旋转加快
she spins faster.
飞旋的中子星是一个巨大的天然发电机
The spinning neutron star is a massive natural electric generator.
其旋转会产生强大的磁场
Its spin creates a powerful magnetic field.
磁力会攫取电子和其它原子粒子
The magnetic force grabs onto electrons and other atomic particles
并以高速将它们抛入太空
and flings them into space at high speeds.
高速粒子无一例外地会喷射辐射
High-speed particles always emit radiation,
在中子星上 它们会成束喷出
and in pulsars, they're coming out in beams.
这些就是我们所看到的脉冲 但我们所见到的
These are the pulses we see, but we see them
只有当这些波束对准我们这方向时
only when the beams are pointed in our direction.
已知有多少中子星？
How many pulsars are known?
约超过1800颗 这数字还在快速增长
It's something over 1,800, and the number is growing rapidly,
因为我们一直都有新的中子星的不断发现
because we continue to discover new pulsars all the time.
然而现存的中子星数目 -
But the number of pulsars that exist--
这些全都是在我们的星系 银河系里发现的 -
and these are all found in our galaxy, the Milky Way--
要远大于那个数目
Is many, many times larger than that,
因为波束 是以电波为主的 是极小的部分
because the beams, that are seen in radio primarily, are very small,
因此我们只看到了所有存在的中子星的极小一部分
and so we only see a tiny fraction of all the pulsars that are out there.
不过每个中子星都有完全不同的旋转速度
But each pulsar has a completely different rotational speed.
最慢的每9.437秒旋转一圈
The slowest rotates once every 9.437 seconds,
而最快的每秒旋转716圈
and the fastest goes around 716 times every second.
如果我们立足其表面
If we stood on its surface,
我们会每小时跑上9700多万英里
we'd be going more than 97 million miles per hour.
那将比我们在地球上的旅行快上1000万倍
That's about 10 million times faster than we travel on Earth.
每颗中子星都有独一无二的旋转
Every pulsar has an absolutely unique spin.
其旋转有特定的速率
It goes around at a given rate,
那就像是人的指纹
and that's just like a fingerprint for an individual.
所以如果你知道了其特有的旋转
So if you know what that characteristic spin is,
你就知道是哪颗脉冲星了
then you know what that pulsar is.
由于所有的脉冲星都有自己的签名
Since all pulsars have their own signatures,
你就可以利用它们来确定你在太空中的位置
you can use them as tools to determine your location in space,
这个想法已被航天局所利用
an idea that has been used by NASA.
我们送入外太阳系的一些航天器
Some of the spacecraft we've sent into the outer parts of the solar system,
如先锋号和旅行者号 都带有太空地图
like Pioneer and Voyager, have had maps of space which
标明了我们太阳系相对于若干脉冲星位置的定位
show our solar system's location relative to the locations of a bunch of pulsars.
太空中的脉冲星可以用来定位地球
The pulsars in space can be used to locate the Earth
无异于我们的GPS设备利用多个卫星
in the same way that our GPS devices use multiple satellites
来定位地面上的位置
to locate a position on the ground.
希望有朝一日
It's hoped one day
另一族太空旅行者能发现其中的一个航天器
another race of space travelers will find one of the spacecraft
读取地图来获悉它来自何处
and read the map to learn where it came from.
足够聪明的外星人能够搞明白我们在哪里
A sufficiently intelligent alien could figure out where we are
通过测量所有这些同样的脉冲星
by measuring all these same pulsars
计算出我们相对它们的位置
and figuring out where we are in relation to them,
因为每颗脉冲星都有一个独特的周期
because each pulsar has a unique period.
每颗脉冲星的独特旋转
The unique spin of each pulsar
也让它们成为了超精确的天文钟
also makes them super-accurate astronomical clocks,
走时优于地球上最好的原子钟
keeping better time than the best atomic clocks here on Earth.
脉冲星之所以精准是因为它们是天然的终极飞轮
Pulsars are so accurate because they're nature's ultimate flywheel.
这是一个普通的自行车轮
This is an ordinary bicycle tire mounted on a repair rack
装在这自行车店里的修理架上
here in this bicycle shop.
这个轮子非常像脉冲星
And this wheel is very much like a pulsar.
来把它转起来
Let's give it a spin.
你看到轮子旋转平稳
So you see the wheel is rotating very smoothly.
有一点点慢下来
There's very little to slow it down.
好 对于太空中的脉冲星来说 几乎没什么让它慢下来
Now, for a pulsar in space, there's almost nothing to slow it down.
请注意轮子的旋转约每秒两圈
Now notice that the wheel is rotating about a couple times a second.
那是普通脉冲星的平均转速
That's the average speed of rotation for an average pulsar.
当然 这轮子只有几英尺的直径
Now, of course, this wheel is only a few feet across,
而真正的脉冲星以同样速度旋转
whereas a real pulsar is spinning at the same speed,
会有曼哈顿那般大
but it's the size of Manhattan.
不过没什么是永恒不变的
But nothing is forever,
即使是脉冲星也会随着时间而减慢
and even pulsars slow down over time,
尽管是非常地缓慢
although they do it very slowly.
阐述脉冲星旋转的同一个轮子
The same bicycle wheel that illustrates the pulsar's spin
还演示了其速度放慢的原因
also demonstrates what makes it slow down.
脉冲星把旋转能转变成辐射
Pulsars convert rotational energy into radiation,
在此过程中 它们就不得不放慢速度
and in the process, they have to slow down.
来看看它是如何作用于这个车轮的
Let's see how it works with the bicycle wheel.
现在轮子转动很快
Now, the wheel is moving pretty quickly.
如果我把手放到边缘
If I put my hand to the rim,
我可以在我的指尖上将转动能转变成热能
I can convert rotational energy to heat energy in my fingers.
好痛
Ouch.
现在车轮慢了下来
Now the wheel has slowed down.
在真正的脉冲星上 比起我的手更像是羽毛轻拂
In a real pulsar, it would be more like the action of a feather than my hand,
因为脉冲星的能量丧失非常缓慢
because pulsars lose energy very, very slowly.
脉冲星 每秒旋转一次
A pulsar, spinning once every second,
有可能百万年里只放慢百分之三秒
may slow down by about only three hundreths of a second in a million years.
不过 偶尔 脉冲星确实会稍有加速
Occasionally, though, a pulsar may actually speed up slightly
这种现象与中子星的星壳有关
in a phenomenon linked to a neutron star's crust,
一层比钢铁坚固100亿倍的物质
a layer of matter 10 billion times stronger than steel,
但受制于“星震”
and yet subject to "starquakes."
中子星并非通体都是固体
Neutron stars are not solids all the way through.
它们有一个星壳
They have a crust.
星壳异常坚固
And that crust is incredibly strong.
但是中子星里还是有力道
But there are forces within the neutron star
有可能偶尔会使星壳产生裂缝
that can occasionally cause the crust to crack.
一旦产生裂缝 整个中子星会重新调整自己
When it cracks, the whole neutron star readjusts itself,
中子星的旋转会产生变化
and it produces a change in the rotation of the neutron star.
我们称其为脉冲星的自转突变
We call it a glitch.
星壳破裂
The crust is cracked.
中子星上就会产生星震
There has been a starquake on this neutron star.
尽管脉冲星的奇异世界里
Though the strange world of pulsars
包括了诸如自转突变和星震之类的有趣事件
includes intriguing events like glitches and starquakes,
但你还是很难在望远镜捕获到它们时
you'd hardly know it from the tiny blinks seen
从所看到的细微的闪烁中了解它们
when they're captured by telescopes.
不过脉冲星在把致命的辐射
But what happens when pulsars
抛入宇宙云里时会发生什么情况呢？
are hurling deadly radiation into cosmic clouds
先前其母星随着太空中的巨大爆发
after their parent stars have ripped holes in the galaxy
已经在星系中撕开了大口
with their massive explosions in space?
又会对挡道的芸芸众生有何影响呢？
What will their impact be on any living beings in their path?
超新星的致命爆发无限精彩
The deadly explosions of supernovas are endlessly fascinating.
它们是暮年恒星的咆哮
They are the violent screams of aging stars,
怒其渐渐老去
outraged at having to grow old.
强烈的爆发不只是杀死挡道的芸芸众生
The powerful blasts would do more than kill any living beings in their path.
超新星会抹去围绕着爆发恒星的
A supernova would wipe out all traces of any civilization
行星上的所有文明的痕迹
on a planet in orbit around the exploding star.
星系里充满了这些爆发留下的色彩斑斓的余波
The galaxy is full of the colorful aftereffects of these explosions.
它们是巨大的星际残骸云 称为超新星遗迹
They are gigantic clouds of stellar debris called supernova remnants.
你要是想搜寻脉冲星 那里是最佳之处
And if you're searching for a pulsar, that's the best place to look.
脉冲星确实可以在超新星遗迹找到
Pulsars are actually found in supernova remnants.
那是因为脉冲星形成于超新星
That's because pulsars are formed in a supernova,
爆发的恒星
an exploding star.
虽然有些脉冲星加速远离
While some pulsars speed away from
或另立门户于它们的超新星遗迹
or simply outlive their supernova remnants,
但其它则还是旋转在遗迹之中
others remain spinning inside them.
在那里 它们照亮了周围的壳体
There, they light up the surrounding shell
创造出所谓的脉冲星风星云
and create what's called a pulsar wind nebula.
脉冲星产生的风完全不是我们在地球上所认为的东西
The wind from a pulsar is not quite like what we think of on Earth,
那是空气流动
which is air blowing.
这个风却是由粒子和辐射组成的
Instead it's a wind made of particles and radiation.
但是风速极高
But it's blowing out at very high speeds,
大大快于我们在地球上的任何东西
much faster than anything we have here on Earth,
速度高到携带大量的能量
high enough that it carries a lot of energy,
能量与爆发恒星的残留的物质相互作用
and the energy interacts with the material
使之点亮
that's left over from the exploding star to cause it to light up.
迄今为止 脉冲星风星云中最壮观的例子
By far, the most spectacular example
我们所知的就是蟹状星云
of a pulsar wind nebula that we know about is the Crab Nebula,
它有一颗旋转的中子星在其中央
which has a spinning neutron star at its center,
就是它让整体熠熠生辉
and that's what energizes the whole thing.
蟹状星云是著名的超新星遗迹
The Crab Nebula is a famous supernova remnant
出自公元1054年出现的超新星
from the supernova that occurred in the year 1054 A.D.,
亚洲天文学家有过研究
studied by Asian astronomers.
超新星本身可见于天上
The supernova itself could be seen in the sky
历时数周直至逐渐消失
for weeks before fading away,
没想到近700年后被重新发现
only to be rediscovered nearly 700 years later
成为了超新星遗迹 观察只能通过望远镜了
as a supernova remnant, visible only through telescopes.
蟹状星云中的脉冲星发现于1968年
The pulsar in the Crab Nebula was discovered in 1968,
首颗脉冲星发现后不久
very soon after the first pulsar.
它证实了脉冲星出自超新星的说法
And it confirmed the theory that pulsars came from supernovas.
从地球上看 蟹状星云中的脉冲星
Seen from the Earth, the pulsar in the Crab Nebula
貌似一个微不足道的小不点
looks like an insignificant speck.
在其被确定为脉冲星之前 没有人意识到
Before it was identified as a pulsar, no one realized
它居然是每秒闪烁30次
it was actually blinking on and off 30 times a second.
在一张典型的长曝光的望远镜照片里
In a typical long-exposure photo from a telescope,
它只是表现为普通的恒星
it registers simply as an ordinary star.
每秒30次太快了
Well, 30 times a second is too fast
谁都没法看清蟹状星云的闪烁
for anyone to actually see the Crab Pulsar blinking.
取而代之的是 我们必须用上一种高速摄影技术
Instead, we have to use a kind of high-speed photographic technique
叫做光子计数器
called a photon counter.
它能够拍摄飞快 足以
That's able to take pictures fast enough
看清脉冲星的闪烁
to actually see the pulsar blinking on and off.
它会呈现出
It appears to be on
打开时脉冲星光束转向我们
when the pulsar beam rotates toward us,
关闭时光束转离了
and it's off when the beam rotates away.
难以置信的是脉冲星的威力
What's incredible is the power of the pulsar.
我们看到蟹状星云里的一切都栩栩生辉
Everything we see in the Crab Nebula is glowing
源于那颗旋转的中子星源源不断的能量
because of the energy streaming out of that single spinning neutron star.
蟹状星云中央的中子星
The neutron star in the middle of the Crab Nebula
直径也许就10英里
has a diameter of perhaps 10 miles,
但却照亮了周围数光年的气体
but it's lighting up the gas around it for several light-years.
这个小不点
So this eensy-beensy thing
点亮了周围一个巨大的区域
is lighting up a tremendously large region around it
因为所有的高能带电粒子都出自它
because of all the energetic charged particles coming away from it.
脉冲星点亮的超新星遗迹
The pulsar is lighting up a supernova remnant
直径6光年
six light-years in diameter,
相当于近38万个天文单位
equivalent to nearly 380,000 astronomical units.
一个天文单位 简称AU
An astronomical unit, or an AU,
通常用来描述宇宙中的距离
Is commonly used to describe distance in the cosmos.
科罗拉多州丹佛市威尔
Will W. of Denver, Colorado,
询问《宇宙》节目：天文单位是啥东西？
wants to ask "The Universe" just what an AU is.
威尔 了解一下有好处
Will, that's a useful thing to know.
我一下子的回答就是天文单位
My snappy answer is that an astronomical unit
有点搞脑筋的
is one heck of a big apartment.
不过 言归正传 天文单位
But, really, the astronomical unit
就是地球与太阳之间的平均距离
is the average distance between the Earth and the Sun.
那约是9300万英里 或等于1.5亿公里
Now, that's about 93 million miles, or, equivalently, 150 million kilometers.
蟹状星云深处的混沌
The chaos deep inside the Crab Nebula is revealed by time-lapse pictures
在X射线和可见光下的延时摄像中暴露无遗
in both X-rays and visible light.
旋转恒星的脉冲星风在其赤道周围产生了冲击波
The spinning star's pulsar wind creates shock waves around its equator,
此时两极不停地喷出汹涌的喷射
while polar jets are shooting out in turbulent streams.
因此这是个非常具有活力的星系  令人激动
So this is a very dynamic system, an exciting one.
天文学中 人人都在研究蟹状星云
And everybody in astronomy studies the Crab Nebula.
与大多数脉冲星一样
Like most pulsars,
蟹状星云里的那个也在逐渐放缓
the one inside the Crab Nebula is gradually slowing down,
但约有10%的脉冲星被发现有一个大规模的加速过程
but about 10% of all pulsars have found a method of speeding up in a big way.
它们被称为毫秒脉冲星
They're called millisecond pulsars.
毫秒脉冲星就是我们所谓的再生脉冲星
Millisecond pulsars are what we call recycled pulsars.
它们曾经是普通的脉冲星
They used to be ordinary pulsars.
它们停止了脉冲
They stopped pulsing,
随后因为它们处在一个双星系里
and then because they were in a binary system,
也就是说 附近有一颗恒星
that is, there was another star nearby
它们会从中窃取一些物质
that they could steal some mass from,
从而旋转起来
they're spun up.
因而它们就加速到毫秒级速度
So their speed increases to millisecond speeds.
每当有东西落入脉冲星时 它就会得到一次刺激
Each time something falls onto the pulsar, it gets a kick,
因为来自同伴的星际物质旋入了其中
because the stellar matter from the companion swirls onto it,
而不是直接落在其表面
instead of dropping straight to the surface.
旋转的自行车轮
The rotating bicycle wheel
表明了脉冲星的加速过程
illustrates how the process makes the pulsar speed up.
车轮在旋转
The wheel is spinning,
我的手就像是来自伴星的物质
and my hand is like the matter from the companion star.
因为它具有旋转的势头
Because it has rotational momentum,
它转向里面 如这样打击恒星
it swirls inward and strikes the star like this,
增加了它的转速
increasing its speed of rotation.
并不像这样突然刹车
It doesn't drop down like this.
实际上 毫秒脉冲星获得的速度是相当惊人的
In nature, the speeds attained by millisecond pulsars are breathtaking.
脉冲星每秒旋转数百圈
Pulsars spin several hundred times a second,
甚至最快的会高达每秒上千圈
even up to maybe a thousand times a second for the fastest ones.
那可非同寻常
That's very unusual,
因为你想想曼哈顿那般大小的东西
because you're talking about something the size of maybe Manhattan,
每秒钟旋转数百圈
spinning a few hundred times a second.
它会让你眼花缭乱
That would make you pretty dizzy.
还有比毫秒脉冲星更为奇特的
Even more exotic than millisecond pulsars
怪兽 叫做磁星
are the strange beasts known as magnetars.
磁星极为罕见
Magnetars are extremely rare.
事实上 我们在1979年之前对其一无所知
In fact, we didn't even know about any of them until 1979.
甚至在当时 我们都不确定我们看到了什么
And even then, we weren't sure exactly what we were looking at.
现在我们知道在我们星系4000亿颗恒星里头
Now we know of only about 15 magnetars
只有约15颗磁星
amongst the 400 billion stars in our galaxy.
脉冲星 已知一开始就具有很强的磁场
Pulsars are known to have strong magnetic fields to begin with,
但磁星将磁性推向了极致
but magnetars take magnetism to the extreme.
磁星的磁场极其强烈
The magnetic field of a magnetar is intense.
它是地球磁场强度的上千万亿倍
It's a thousand million million times the magnetic field strength of the Earth.
现在 要是附近有一颗磁星
Now, if there were a magnetar anywhere nearby,
那就会抹去全世界所有的信用卡的磁性
it would de-magnetize all the credit cards in the world.
不过信用卡对人类已无太大的用处了
But credit cards wouldn't be of much use to humans
他们每一个分子都已被磁星给拆开了
whose very molecules may be pulled apart by a magnetar.
磁星具有整个宇宙间最强的磁场
Magnetars have the strongest magnetic field in the whole universe.
不清楚人类究竟能否生存在
It's unclear exactly if humans could even live
那样强的磁场之中
amongst a magnetic field that strong,
因为磁性会将水分子拆开
because the magnetism tends to pull water molecules apart
变成拉长的结构
into elongated structures.
难料人类是否还能存活
It's doubtful that people could even live.
仿佛磁星和毫秒脉冲星还不够怪异
And as if magnetars and millisecond pulsars weren't bizarre enough,
在银河系的星系插曲中
in the Milky Way's galactic sideshow,
还有其它怪胎 更令人瞠目结舌
there are other freaks, even more mind-blowing.
有机会发现孪生脉冲星
What are the chances of finding twin pulsars,
带有行星的脉冲星
pulsars with planets,
以及与《感恩而死》的鼓手合作的脉冲星吗？
and pulsars joining the drummer of The Grateful Dead?
去掉节拍
Take the click off.
来见见米奇.哈特 一位长期鼓手
Meet Mickey Hart, longtime drummer,
他的成名作是《感恩而死》
who first gained fame with The Grateful Dead,
现在在制作太空中的脉冲星节拍的音乐
and now makes music to the beat of pulsars from space.
我想与宇宙组织互动
I wanted to interact with the fabric of the universe,
把我们打击进创世的东西 种子声音
the things that blew us into creation, the seed sounds.
这些电磁波 我们已经将其转换成了声波
So these electromagnetic waves we've transferred into sonic waves.
脉冲星特别有趣
Pulsars are especially interesting.
脉冲星发出的那些电磁波
Those electromagnetic waves from pulsars
传给我们的最明显的就是电波的形式
reach us most clearly in the form of radio waves,
划过苍穹
sweeping across the sky
奇异的波束使脉冲星脱颖而出
in the freakish beams that make pulsars stand out.
脉冲星产生大量的电波
Pulsars produce a lot of radio waves,
完全不同于普通的恒星
and that's quite unlike normal stars.
普通恒星的光芒几乎都是可见光波
Normal stars shine mostly at visible optical wavelengths.
因此你一旦看到有明亮的射电源出现
So when you see a bright radio source out there,
就会引起你的注意
it captures your attention.
另外要是有哔哔哔的声音
And if in addition, it's going beep beep beep,
那就真的抓住你的眼球了
then it really captures your attention.
我们还非常幸运 电波可以
We're also very lucky that radio waves can
让自己经过我们星系的漫长距离
make it through long distances in our galaxy
不受气体尘埃的干扰
without being affected by the intervening gas and dust.
它们还让自己经过我们的大气层
And they make it through our own atmosphere as well
而没有任何干扰
without any trouble.
不过也许关于脉冲星电波束最令人兴奋的
But perhaps what's most exciting about pulsar radio beams
就是它们来自数百光年以外
is that they come from hundreds of light-years away.
不过要将它们输入耳机或扬声器
But pipe them into a set of headphones or speakers,
我们才能真正听到它们
and we can actually listen to them.
对于较慢的 你所听到的
For slow ones, what you hear
就是每一圈一次的扬声器的撞击
is a bump out of the speaker every once--every rotation.
但对于最高频率 你听到的是连续的音调
But for the highest frequency ones, you hear a continuous tone.
这是典型的脉冲星的神秘声音
This is the unearthly sound of a typical pulsar
每秒旋转1.4圈
rotating 1.4 times each second.
转换成音频 脉冲星的电波信号
Converted to audio, the pulsar's radio signal
就是催眠 重复的滴答声
is a hypnotic, repetitious tick.
然而调高频率 听听这颗毫秒脉冲星
But turn up the frequency and listen to this millisecond pulsar,
每秒旋转174圈
spinning 174 times per second,
快得让其节拍都混在了一起 变成了刺耳的声调
so fast that its ticks blend together to generate a ragged note
那几乎就不成为音乐了
that's on the edge of turning into music.
那确实就是我们听到的船帆座脉冲星的声音
That's especially true when we listen to the Vela Pulsar.
船帆座脉冲星有一个很棒的节奏
The Vela Pulsar has a terrific rhythm to it.
很难想象这种声音居然出自一颗转动的恒星
It's hard to imagine this sound coming from a spinning star of all things.
几乎让你欲翩翩起舞
It almost makes you want to get up and dance.
船帆座脉冲星带着宇宙节拍旋转在
The Vela Pulsar is spinning with its cosmic beat
一个巨大的超新星遗迹的中心
at the center of a giant supernova remnant,
其致命的辐射横扫其周围的星际气体和尘埃
where its killer radiation tears through the galactic gas and dust around it.
该超新星爆发于1.1万年前
The supernova exploded 11,000 years ago,
如今该脉冲星是所见X射线中最为壮观的
and today the pulsar is most spectacular when seen in X-rays.
每秒旋转11圈 延时照片表明
Rotating 11 times a second, time-lapse photos show
它正喷发出物质喷射
that it's shooting out a jet of material,
像失控的水龙划过太空
whipping through space like an uncontrolled fire hose.
船帆座脉冲星不同凡响的宇宙节拍
The unusual space beat of the Vela Pulsar
对米奇.哈特是特殊的启发
is a special turn-on for Mickey Hart,
他现在正将其作为其最新作品的基础
who's now making it the basis for part of his latest project.
啊 船帆座脉冲星非常适合作曲
Well, Vela Pulsar, it's really made for composition,
因为它具有有规律的节奏
because it has a regular rhythm.
音质 已经增强 感觉良好
And sonically, it's been enhanced, and it feels good,
你可以把它放到曲子里
and you can use it in composition.
所以我首先准备做船帆座
So I went to the Vela first thing.
哈特把一些简单的脉冲星声音用在了
Hart used some simple pulsar sounds
在感恩而死乐队2009年巡回演出中
during The Dead's 2009 concert tour,
现在他把它们开发成了古怪的乐曲
and now he's building them into mind-bending tracks
作为其《Global Drum Project》专辑即将面世的续集
for an upcoming sequel to his Global Drum Project album.
他的脉冲星声音来自外星智慧搜索中心（SETI）
His pulsar sounds came from the SETI Institute,
那里负责外星智能的搜索
which leads the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.
我去过SETI
I went to SETI,
他们让我听到了我一直在寻求的东西
and they led me to the sounds that I was looking for.
我以前确实没有钻研过宇宙中的声音
I really hadn't delved into the sounds of the universe before.
他们那里恰好有它的主脉
They just had the mother lode of it there,
他们和我一起分享了它
and they shared it with me.
于是我将其转成了音乐
And then I turned it into music.
一旦整个事情摆上了日程
Once all of these things started to come my way,
我就意识到 告诉你 宇宙在歌唱
I realized that, you know, the universe was singing.
它对我既是精神上的东西 又是娱乐
It's a spiritual thing for me as well as entertainment.
就是说 它是乐趣 与宇宙共舞 - 乐趣无穷
I mean, it's fun, working with the cosmos--beyond fun.
那是我深刻的心灵体验
It's a deep spiritual experience for me.
宇宙合唱团变得越来越大
The cosmic chorus gets much bigger
当其来到叫做杜鹃47的地方时
when it comes to a place called 47 Tucanae,
那是南方星座杜鹃座里的一个球形星团
a globular cluster of stars in the southern constellation Toucana, the Toucan.
该星团在1.6万光年之外
The cluster is 16,000 light-years away
200万颗恒星挤在120光年直径的球形里
with 2 million stars packed into a sphere 120 light-years across.
不可思议的是 杜鹃47居然有22颗毫秒脉冲星
Incredibly, 47 Tucanae has 22 millisecond pulsars,
个个都在离奇的星际合唱团里产生着自己的音符
each generating its own musical note in the bizarre stellar choir.
为了让毫秒脉冲星产生音符
To get a millisecond pulsar producing a musical note,
你就需要让那种脉冲星
you need to start with the kind of pulsar
高速将孪生伴星里的物质吸入到自己这里
whipped up in speed by matter spilling onto it from a binary companion star.
好 为了做到这一点 你必须要有很多靠近的恒星
Well, in order to do this, you have to have lots of nearby stars.
要做到这一点还有比星团更好的地方吗？
And what better place to do that than in a star cluster?
因此杜鹃47之类的东西
So something like 47 Tucanae,
是恒星靠近的巨大集合体
which is a tremendously large collection of stars nearby,
是中子星变成毫秒脉冲星的理想之地
is an ideal place to have neutron stars turn into millisecond pulsars.
星团里的脉冲星发出的大合唱
The collective tune from the cluster's pulsars
是奇妙的太空咏叹调
is a strangely haunting song from space,
由其22个风格各异的旋转所谱写
generated by their 22 unique and different spins.
虽然整个星系里的毫秒脉冲星
While millisecond pulsars throughout the galaxy
通常都有普通恒星作为孪生伴星
usually have normal stars as binary companions,
但还是有一个双星系是一个真正的怪胎
there is one known binary system that's a true freak,
因为它有一颗脉冲星与另一颗脉冲星相配对
because it has a pulsar paired with another pulsar.
发现于2003年 唯一已知的双脉冲星
Discovered in 2003, the only known double pulsar
形成于一颗毫秒脉冲星同伴变成超新星之时
formed when a millisecond pulsar's companion went supernova.
现在这两颗脉冲星相互环绕
And now the two pulsars orbit each other
距离非常紧凑 可以装进我们的太阳里
in a space so tight, they would fit inside our Sun.
虽然脉冲星会有伴星
While pulsars can have companion stars,
或伴脉冲星
or companion pulsars,
事情变得更加怪异了 如果我们意识到
things get even stranger when we realize
即使是经历了超新星爆发 其中有些实际上带有行星
that even after a supernova explosion, some of them actually have planets.
脉冲星没准是你期望找到行星的最后的地方
A pulsar is sort of the last place you'd expect to find a planet,
因为产生脉冲星的恰恰是超新星爆发
because what happens to create a pulsar is a supernova explosion.
因此要是普通恒星恰好有行星在其周围
So if the original star happened to have any planets around them,
就有可能已经被超新星给炸飞了
they probably would have been blasted apart by the supernova.
然而在1992年 我们太阳系外所发现的首颗行星
But in 1992, the very first planets discovered outside our solar system
就看到围绕着一颗脉冲星
were found around a pulsar.
波多黎各阿雷西博的巨大的射电望远镜
The giant radio telescope in Arecibo, Puerto Rico,
被用来精确测量一颗脉冲星的计时
was used to precisely measure the timing of a pulsar,
它距离地球980光年
980 light-years from Earth.
它在不断变化 会时而快一点 时而慢一点
It was changing, going a little faster and a little slower.
表明了除了这颗脉冲星本身 还有什么东西存在
And that implied that there was something else besides this pulsar itself.
它并不孤单
It was not isolated.
原来的却有一颗行星存在
It turned out to be indeed a planet.
现在的计算表明 至少有三颗行星
Calculations now show there are at least three planets
围绕着该脉冲星 怀疑还有第四颗
in orbit around the pulsar, and a fourth is suspected.
脉冲星的超新星可能已经摧毁了其恒星原来的行星
The pulsar's supernova may have destroyed its star's original planets,
但是新的形成了 显然是脱胎于
but new ones formed, apparently out of debris
星系爆发所残留的碎片
left over from the system's explosion.
脉冲星是极端力量的体现
Pulsars are the embodiment of extreme forces
一旦它变成与众不同的星体后
when it comes to individual stars.
然而当你将这种能量提高到整个星系后 会是啥情况呢？
But what happens when you ramp up such power to the level of an entire galaxy?
在那个级别上 我们发现了类星体
At that scale, we find the quasars.
是什么让它们在宇宙中鹤立鸡群的呢？
What makes them outshine everything else in the cosmos?
为何科学家会说在每一个的中心
And why do scientists say that in the heart of each one
都存在着一个怪兽呢？
there sits a monster?
虽然脉冲星和磁星之类的东西
While things like pulsars and magnetars
在宇宙的奇怪星群中十分抢眼
stand out as freakish stars in the cosmos,
但更为怪异的天体深藏不露
even stranger objects lurk much farther away
那里就是类星体所呆的地方
where the quasars live.
类星体是星系明亮耀眼的核心
A quasar is a blindingly bright core of a galaxy
巨大的黑洞在其中央
that has a giant black hole in the center,
它极其明亮
and it's extremely bright.
其亮度可以达到星系里所有恒星放在一起的
It can be as bright as 10 to 1,000 times brighter
总亮度的10到1000倍
than all the stars in the galaxy put together.
这张哈勃望远镜照片证明了类星体可以有多亮
This Hubble Telescope photo proves just how bright a quasar can be.
两个突出的天体看上去几乎一样
The two prominent objects look almost the same,
但一个只是一颗恒星 或许就100光年以外
but one is only a star, perhaps 100 light-years away,
而另一个则是类星体 在90亿光年之外
while the other is a quasar, 9 billion light-years away.
和脉冲星一样 类星体引起天文学家最早注意
Like pulsars, quasars were first noticed by astronomers
是作为强大的电波发射源
as strong sources of radio waves.
最早的是叫做3C273的射电源
The very first was a radio source called 3C273.
3C273是啥东东？
Well, what's a 3C273?
剑桥射电望远镜收藏有电波的编目 -
The Cambridge Radio Telescope collected a catalog of radio--
出现在空中的明亮的射电源
bright radio sources that were seen in the sky,
它是第三个剑桥编目
and it was the third Cambridge catalog,
其编号273是一个明亮的射电源
and its item number 273 was a bright radio source.
人们设法去弄明白 这个射电源是啥玩意？
People were trying to figure out, what is this radio source?
当光学望远镜指向其位置时
When optical telescopes were pointed at its position,
他们所看到的貌似一颗恒星
all they saw was what looked like a star.
后来意识到这个天体非常遥远
Then when it was realized that this object was very far away,
在10亿光年以外 事实上...
more than a billion light-years away, in fact...
那意味着它们实在是强大
It meant that their true power,
它们每秒钟所释放的能量
the amount of energy they put out per second,
其功率 十分巨大
their wattage, was enormous,
因为看上去很亮 但又十分遥远
because to look bright and yet be far away
那就是你看到的确实是一个强大的天体
means that you've got to be really a powerful object.
它会是什么呢？
What could it be?
现在 3C273被视为一个十分明亮的蓝色恒星
Now, 3C273 was identified with a rather bright, bluish star.
它表现为恒星模样
So it looked star-like,
但恒星一般不会发射电波
but stars don't generally emit radio waves,
因此它被称为类星射电源
so it was called a quasi-stellar radio source.
类星射电源名字太长了
Quasi-stellar radio source was just too long a name,
所以它被简称为类星体
and so it was shortened to quasar,
不过 天哪 听上去不是很不错吧？
but, golly, doesn't that have a nice sound?
类星体的确是个了不起的术语
Quasar is really a great term,
因为它意味着某种奇怪 与众不同的东西
because it implies something exotic and unusual,
的确就是这些天体的情况
and that's really what these objects are.
它们是巨大的黑洞 在不停地吞噬周围的物质
They are huge black holes that are eating material around them
放射出大量的光
and radiating huge amounts of light that can be seen
几乎在整个可观察到的宇宙间都能看到
almost all the way across the observable universe.
黑洞吞噬类星体里的星系气体
The black hole consuming galactic gas inside the quasar
贪得无厌
is so violently ravenous,
天文学家给了它一个可怕的诨号
astronomers have given it a frightening nickname.
类星体里的黑洞通常被称为怪兽
The black holes inside quasars are often called monsters.
那是因为它们非常庞大
And that's because they're very massive.
它们是我们太阳质量的百万到十亿倍
They're a million to a billion times the mass of our Sun,
它们贪婪地吞噬着周围的物质
and they're voraciously devouring the material around them.
因此它们的行为就好象是怪兽
So they're sort of behaving like monsters.
类星体被认为是由星系中心的黑洞提供动力的
The quasar is said to be powered by the black hole at a galaxy's center.
有东西如此明亮又十分黑暗的概念
The notion of something so bright that is also black
貌似自相矛盾的说法
seems like a contradiction in terms.
我们知道黑洞是非常致密和庞大的天体
We know that black holes are objects that are so dense and massive
具有非常强的引力
and have such strong gravity
连光都无法逃脱它们
that not even light can escape from them.
所以那让我们怀疑
So that makes us wonder,
黑洞怎么可能支配所有东西呢？
how can black holes power anything at all?
答案就在于气体在落入黑洞时
And the answer is that gas, as it falls into the black hole,
实际上会在落入之前发射出能量
can actually radiate energy before it falls in.
在其落入后 就消失了
After it falls in, it's gone.
其发生的过程就是摩擦
The way this happens is through friction.
要是我用双手放在一起快速搓揉
So if I take my hands and rub them together very quickly,
就会产生很多热量
that produces a lot of heat.
现在落入黑洞的物质
Now, the material that falls into a black hole
旋入并自我摩擦
spirals in and rubs against itself,
其速度极高
and it's moving at extremely high speeds.
因而 就类星体而言
And so, in the case of a quasar,
我们会看到气体相互摩擦 速度极高
we have gas that's rubbing together and moving at very high speeds.
因此 这样一来 它可以将自身加热到
And so, in doing so, it can heat itself up
上百万度
to even millions of degrees,
就能够使其发出极其明亮的光
which can cause it to glow very, very brightly.
天文学家确信所有的星系
Astronomers are confident that there are giant black holes
中心都有巨大的黑洞
in the center of all galaxies.
那么为何所有的星系里并不同时都有类星体呢？
So why aren't there quasars in all galaxies, too?
为了得到类星体 你需要有两件东西
To get a quasar, you need two things.
一 你需要有一个巨大的黑洞在星系中央
One, you need a huge, massive black hole at the center of the galaxy.
但是你还需要有补给的气体落入黑洞
But you also need a supply of gas to fall onto that black hole.
如果周围没有足够的物质
If there isn't enough material around,
如果黑洞已经基本上吃掉了周围的食物
if the black hole has basically eaten all its food around it,
于是就没有什么能发光了 没有什么能发热了
then there's nothing to shine, there's nothing to glow.
就不会成为明亮的类星体了
It won't be a bright quasar.
因而就会是 有可能是
So there could be, and probably are,
黑洞处在大多数星系的中央
black holes at the center of most galaxies.
但要是没有燃料补给 它们就不会成为类星体的
But if there's no fuel for them, they won't be quasars.
不过宇宙中有条件可能使类星体
But there are conditions in the universe that may make a quasar reignite,
在其宿主星系中央的气体枯竭后很久之后再次点燃
long after the gas in its host galaxy's center gets used up.
做到这一点的一个有效办法就是两个星系碰撞在一块
And one promising way of doing this is by slamming two galaxies together.
我们知道星系的碰撞
We know that galaxies collide.
在其发生时 就会产生一个宇宙大撞车
And when that happens, it creates a big cosmic smash-up
会将物质驱进星系的中心
that drives material down into the center of the galaxy.
该场景有可能适用于我们自己的银河系
The scenario could apply to our own Milky Way Galaxy,
它正处在与仙女座的碰撞过程之中
which is on a collision course with Andromeda,
那是隔壁的巨大螺旋星系
the giant spiral next door.
在50到60亿年里
In five or six billion years,
仙女座星系会和银河系合并
when the Andromeda Galaxy starts merging with the Milky Way Galaxy,
能够想象到有足够的气体被推向
it's conceivable that enough gas will be pushed
超大质量黑洞的中心
toward the central supermassive black holes,
使它们变成类星体
that they'll turn into quasars.
现在 仙女座星系
Now, the Andromeda Galaxy
可能会是两个类星体中较为明亮的
will probably be the brighter of the two quasars,
因为仙女座里的黑洞质量远远超过
because Andromeda has a much more massive black hole
我们的银河系
than our Milky Way Galaxy.
如果仙女座一旦与我们银河系合并变成类星体的话
If Andromeda turns into a quasar when it's merging with the Milky Way Galaxy,
可以想象它就会相当于满月的亮度
it's conceivable that it'll be comparable to the full moon in brightness
它就在一万光年之外
when it's 10,000 light-years away.
哇
Wow.
即使近在一万光年之外
Even as close as 10,000 light-years away,
我们还是看不到仙女座类星体的星盘
we wouldn't see the Andromeda quasar's disk
如我们所看到的满月那样
as we can with the full moon.
相反 它会表现为璀璨明亮的恒星
Instead, it will appear as an intensely bright star,
忽隐忽现 因为大气层的波动 宛如其他恒星那样
flickering, due to atmospheric fluctuations, as all stars do.
不过 难以置信的是 如果类星体形成于我们的星系中央
But, incredibly, if a quasar forms at the center of our own galaxy,
我们是根本看不见的
we wouldn't see it at all.
它有可能很明亮 但是有太多的尘埃
As bright as it may be, there is so much dust
在地球与星系核之间
between the Earth and the galactic core,
类星体发出的光会躲开我们
quasar's light would be hidden from us,
此时仙女座类星体则会照亮天空
while Andromeda's would light up the sky.
如果我们未来出现一个局部的类星体
If there is a local quasar in our future,
有可能会采用任何一种形式
it could take any number of different forms.
它们以天体物理喷射轰击太空
They bombard space with astrophysical jets
起名字听上去像是神话生物 比如耀变体和巨龙
and sound like mythical creatures with names like blazars and DRAGNs.
它们叙说的故事带我们穿越宇宙史诗
The stories they tell lead us through the cosmological epic
我们来到时间的起点
where we arrive at the beginning of time
来一睹类星体是如何在宇宙诞生的那一刻帮助构建宇宙的
to find out how quasars helped build the universe at its very birth.
在近50年的搜索中
In nearly 50 years of searching,
天文学家已经发现了近百万个类星体
astronomers have discovered nearly a million quasars
遍布整个宇宙
scattered throughout the universe.
结果是 它们表现出各种各样的形式
And as it turns out, they come in a wide variety of forms.
类星体只是所谓的活跃的
A quasar is just one of a family of objects
星系核天体家族的一员 家族全都是由掉入
called active galactic nuclei, all of which are powered by material
星系中心巨大黑洞的物质来驱动的
falling onto huge black holes at the center of galaxies.
其中超大质量黑洞吞噬
The rate at which supermassive black holes can swallow material
星系中央的物质的速度可以改变整个空间
in the centers of galaxies can vary all over the place.
那些并不闪闪发光的
The ones that don't glow so brightly
叫做活跃的星系核 并非类星体
are called active galactic nuclei, but not quasars.
活跃的星系核最离奇的特点之一
One of the most bizarre features of active galactic nuclei
其中某些喷射出高速物质喷射
are the high-speed jets of material shooting out from some of them.
3C273 发现的首个类星体 就具有喷射
3C273, the first quasar to be discovered, has a jet.
它不仅隐约出现在可见光图像中
It's only subtly apparent in the optical image,
而且在X光 红外线及无线电望远镜观察下尤为生动
but becomes more vivid when seen by X-ray, infrared, and radio telescopes.
类星体喷射是天王星上的奥秘
Quasar jets are an astronomical mystery.
多年来 科学家绞尽脑汁
For years, scientists have racked their brains
去确切地解释它们是如何产生的
to explain exactly how they are generated.
如同脉冲星一样 自行车店里的飞轮
As with pulsars, a spinning wheel in a bicycle shop
解释了他们认为发挥作用的力量
illustrates the forces they believe are at work.
垂直的轮辐表示类星体磁场的磁力线
A vertical spoke represents a force line in the quasar's magnetic field.
类星体的喷射或许需要两件事才能形成
The jets from quasars probably require two things to form.
首先是围绕黑洞的气体盘
The first is a disk of gas that orbits the black hole.
其次是固定在气体盘上的磁力线
The second are magnetic field lines that are anchored to the disk.
以下就是我们对其工作的认为
Here's how we think it works.
带电粒子喜欢磁力线
Charged particles love magnetic field lines.
这样粒子会被束缚在磁力线上
So the particles get tied to the field line,
在其旋转时 它们就会被吹上去 远离气体盘
and as it rotates, they get blown upward, away from the disk.
好 最终 磁力线缠在一起
Now, eventually, the field line will twist around,
将物质压缩成一个紧紧的圆柱
forcing the matter into a tight column,
也就是天文学家所谓的天体物理喷射
or what astronomers call an astrophysical jet.
喷射里的带电粒子高速运动
The charged particles in the jet are moving at high speeds
能够在遥远处看到
and can be seen from great distances.
几乎就像是类星体试图引人注意
It's almost as if the quasar were trying to get noticed
在做一些广告
by doing some advertising,
就像地球上本地商贩的作为
just as a local retailer might do on Earth.
这种广告小玩意叫做空气舞者
This advertising gadget is called an air dancer.
它在地球上招人注意就像类星体喷出的喷射
It gets our attention here on Earth like the jet out of a quasar.
事实上 其工作之道是一样的
And, in fact, the way it works is similar.
编织布袋的行为就像类星体所产生的扭曲的磁场
The fabric rippler acts like the twisted magnetic field generated by the quasar.
里面的空气顺着布袋的内壁
The air inside follows the walls of the rippler
就像带电粒子顺着类星体里的磁力线一般
like the charged particles following the magnetic field lines in the quasar.
其中最大的区别
The big difference is that here,
空气的流动或许是每小时50到60英里
the air is flowing maybe 50 or 60 miles per hour.
类星体喷射中 粒子的运动接近光速
In a quasar jet, the particles are moving at nearly the speed of light.
空气舞者的表演
The air dancer's display
从其电源开始也只延展了12英尺左右
also extends only 12 feet or so from its power source.
类星体或其它活跃的星系核喷出的喷射
A jet coming out of a quasar
不管怎样 都远远伸入太空
or another active galactic nucleus, however, stretches far into space,
它有可能变成一个惊人的现象
where it may turn into an amazing phenomenon
天文学家将其称之为飞龙（DRAGN）
that astronomers call a DRAGN.
DRAGN代表与活跃的星系核有关的双电波源
DRAGN stands for double radio source associated with an active galactic nucleus.
那是长长术语的缩写
That's sort of a long term,
但要是你这些东西的图像
but if you look at pictures of these things,
飞龙（DRAGN）真是恰当不过的了
DRAGN fits much better.
形成它们的是这些物质喷射
What they are formed by is these jets of material
从星系中心的黑洞喷射出来
getting shot out from the black hole at the center of the galaxy,
撞上星系之间的星际介质
slamming into the intergalactic medium in between the galaxies
形成这些巨大的波瓣和热点
and forming these massive lobes and hot spots.
它们可以延展到遥远
They can extend to distances
远超过星系本身的范围
much larger than the size of the galaxy itself.
飞龙的规模令人匪夷所思
The scale of a DRAGN is mind-bending.
典型者首尾之间约有150万光年 -
The typical one is about 1.5 million light-years end to end--
远大于生成它的整个星系
far, far larger than the entire galaxy that's producing it.
如果活跃的星系核
If the active galactic nucleus
缩小到这个篮球这么大
were scaled down to the size of this basketball,
那么飞龙的大小 从一个辐射波瓣到另外一个
then the size of a DRAGN from one radial lobe to the other
依然会是极其巨大
would still be absolutely enormous.
会是约整个地球的大小
It would be about the size of the entire Earth.
大多数飞龙都关联到类星体的堂兄弟 叫做射电星系
Most DRAGNs are linked to quasar cousins called radio galaxies,
因为它们是强大的电波源
since they are strong sources of radio waves.
然而同一家庭里的其他成员
But other members of the same family
是高速天体 叫做耀变体
are high-speed objects called blazars,
它们的喷射几乎直指我们的视线
whose jets are pointed almost directly at our line of sight,
使它们格外明亮
making them incredibly bright.
我们的视线实际上把我们导向有关
And our line of sight actually leads us to the most amazing discovery
耀变体 类星体以及射电星系最惊人的发现
about blazars, quasars, and radio galaxies.
谁会相信这些怪物基本上是一样的呢？
Who would have believed these freaks are all basically alike?
通过研究这所有各类活跃的星系核
From studying all these types of active galactic nuclei,
我们现在认识到 某种意义上 它们可以统统归结为同样的东西
we now realize that, in some sense, they can all be treated as the same thing,
只是变现为不同的形式而已
just viewed in different ways.
尤其是 关键在于视角
In particular, the important thing is the viewing angle,
即物质喷射的角度相对我们观察的角度
or the angle of the jet of material relative to the angle that we look at it.
活跃星系的中心都非常活跃
The centers of active galaxies are all very bright,
但它们有可能看上并不是那样
but they may not seem that way,
因为其核心闪耀的物质
because the shining material at their cores
有可能部分或全部被隐蔽了
can be partially or completely hidden.
我们看到的这种物质包围着炸面包圈状的物质环
This material we see is surrounded by a doughnut-shaped ring of material.
那物质 - 气体 尘埃 云层 - 会阻挡
That material--gas, dust, clouds-- can block the light
真正活跃的中心区域里泄漏出来的光线
from escaping from the central region that's really the active part.
射电星系是其中之一
And a radio galaxy is one of those
其中的炸面包圈阻挡了我们对其核心的能见度
in which the doughnut is blocking our visibility of the central core.
不过对于类星体来说
But in the case of a quasar,
我们正看入炸面包圈的圆孔
we're looking down toward the hole in the doughnut.
那就让我们看到物质
And that allows us to see the material
就围绕着黑洞 那就是类星体
right around the black hole that is the quasar.
如果这个类星体的喷射正对我们
If this quasar has its jet pointed toward us,
那么喷射本身就变得分外明亮
then the jet itself becomes extremely bright.
这就是我们称为耀变体的东西
This is what we would call a blazar.
这三者都是同样的
All three are the same.
唯一的区别就在我们的视角
The only difference is our point of view.
但不管我们的视角如何
But regardless of our viewing angle,
它们共同具有的一个情况就是它们距离遥远
one thing they all have in common is their great distance.
类星体震撼我们的地方
The thing that shocked us about quasars
就是它们遥不可及
was how far away they are.
它们非常明亮
They're so bright,
在那种距离上看它们如此明亮
and to see them that bright at that distance,
它们必定是巨大无比 绝对是怪兽
they must be titanic, absolute monsters.
那么为何这些东西中没有靠近我们的呢？
So why are none of these things nearby us?
最近的类星体在20亿光年之外
The nearest quasar is 2 billion light-years away.
最远的在130亿光年之外
The most distant ones are 13 billion light-years away.
大多数类星体看来距离我们非常遥远
Most quasars are seen at vast distances from us.
那意味着我们看到的它们
That means we're seeing them as they were
是在很久很久以前 当时宇宙非常年轻
a long, long time ago in the past when the universe was very young.
类星体似乎是少年宇宙的居民
Quasars appear to be denizens of the young universe.
星系 在其形成的早期
Galaxies, early in their formation,
似乎已经形成了这些黑洞
seem to have produced these black holes,
黑洞在形成后不久就有了大量的物质吞噬
and the black holes still had a lot of material to eat
因此它们熠熠生辉成为了类星体
shortly after being formed, so they glowed as quasars.
最早的类星体可追溯到大爆炸本身后不久
The earliest quasars date from shortly after the Big Bang itself,
表明它们扮演了重要的角色
suggesting they had an important role to play
伴随宇宙经历了早期成长的烦恼
as the universe endured its early growing pains.
有可能这些超大质量黑洞 就是我们所谓的类星体
It's possible that these supermassive black holes that we call quasars
参与了宇宙结构的创建过程
were part of the process of creating structure in the universe.
该过程没有完全搞明白
The process is not completely understood.
因此由于多数类星体局限在遥远的过去
So with most of the quasars confined to the distant past,
我们认真地研究它们
we study them intensely,
希望它们能散发出宇宙起源的光辉
hoping they'll shed greater light on the origins of the cosmos.
早期的巨大黑洞
The early giant black holes
可能是打造首批星系的引擎之一
may have been among the engines that built the first galaxies,
赋予原始气体的混沌形态
giving form to the chaos of primeval gas
逐步塑造出我们今天所见到的...宇宙
that would take shape in what we now see as... the universe.